The conscious of this is, as I mentioned before, which is a factory.
So again, if you think of a single ten, it's like they're unique. They're single.
Factory, think your large manufacturing plant, right? They're like turning stuff out.
That's what the functions do. They turn out a new set of state that will be used upon every
instantiation. So in other words, factories are not great when you want a share state,
because they're all going to be unique. They're going to be separate states.
That's what you want. That's great. But in the event you're trying to share it, that's where the problem lies.
So has everyone here used some sort of state management before, probably?
Yeah, looks like it. And so for those who are new to this pattern,
the days are patterned, basically, assumes that you have a single ten that you're sharing at the top.
So actually, let me go to, I guess I'll have to use weeks in this one, and we'll flip the task.
And you just use tasks, and then do weeks both. So this is already set up.
The idea here is something that's shared, like the single ten here,
and then you have function that then modify it. So in other words, if we go ahead and say,
I think we had like a fetch, let's see, this is a response fetch, oh gosh, let's see,
we could form model. Maybe this will be fine. If we, this is a post, no, I don't want to put, no,
fetch, here you go, weeks, okay, good enough. And so here, for example, oh,
this fetch week's function, let's take a whole thing. Okay. So inside of here,
we now have this method. I generally like to label my things function, just to kind of separate them
from the variables, something I like to do. So we have this async function for fetching the weeks
for now we are, oh, I guess we need these other pieces, but one moment we need to then grab
those pieces of state here. So we'll grab those, like as such, and we'll export them as well.
And then so these are your actions because they impact state. So they're there. I need the API
base URL. What is that? There it is. Okay, and then we drop that, let's see, that's a constant,
let's store that at the top. And then that's being shared great. And then fetch weeks, fetch, yep,
this is good. That looks like no errors. Okay, perfect. And so usually what happens then is,
so you have this action for being able to fetch weeks. And so you can imagine here, okay,
this was the factory one. If we have a getter say number of weeks, then you would say export
cons, a number of weeks equals computed. And then we go ahead and return weeks.value.length.
And so here we see we're kind of starting to shape up into store a little bit. And so then the
data, the data store model then basically reports that from what you would do here is,
because right now everything is just kind of being shared together, they, you want to be able to
instantiate things, it's kind of the idea. So you would actually export a function called like
use in this case week store. And what it does is, again, you keep your single 10 out here.
But inside of this, you, you basically share this stuff. So your actions and your getters.
But, but, but as such. So return, I would say a week's number of weeks. Yeah, number of weeks.
And then it's at fetch weeks. Yep. And so this would technically be your getters.
This is your actions. And then what you could do, and this is another technique,
there is a helper function from view. That's called read only.
And read only is helpful because when you expose your rest directly, there is a chance that
a developer is going to get sloppy and they're going to try to mutate something. So in this case,
rather than having them hit this directly, what you would do is you actually prevent this from being
exported so that they can directly impact your source of truth. And then you would basically say,
inside of here, weeks is read only weeks. And then I think it was like is loading,
I think more of the other two, week is loading week error. Week is loading, read only. It's
loading, read week error. Read only. Okay. And then comma. And how would this work?
Well, now that we have this, let's see, there are probably some things breaking now. So let's
find out what's breaking. Do do do do. Yep. So I have no idea what this week is. So we can do
that and as we say, okay, we're going to import use what I thought weeks store from composables
use week. And then I would go ahead and initialize it and I'll say, cons week store equals
use week store. And then you see here, there's a bunch of stuff basically ready for us to access.
And so from here weekstore.weeks now works weekstore.weeks. And uh uh uh uh uh uh uh weekstore.
That's weeks. I think that's everything. Okay. And then if I look at the test form
now, put up. I killed the server. Okay.
What did I do wrong? Oh, I know I did wrong. You can't put multiple exports inside of an
export. So meaning uh use week here. I left the keyboard in there unfortunately. So there you go.
That should do it. And then oh yes, back here, back here two tasks. Oh. It's yelling at me.
Why's yelling? Use week does not find an export name weeks. So that means somewhere else is using it,
import weeks. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. You're totally right. Okay. That's that's the problem. Okay.
That's okay. We're going to we're going to be going to be diligent about this. Use weekstore. You're right.
That, that, that, that, and then
although this is already I see repetition there for sure. Fetch weeks is definitely being repeated here.
Weekstore. Weeks. We store week store week store. Although I did not initialize it yet. So this is
why it's so airing out. So we can go ahead. Don't miss this anymore. Yep. It's a times week store.
It was used week store. All right. Now this should be healthier. Good call out. Thank you for that.
Weeks. Yep. Right. And that is, that's everything. Okay. All right. I have to do it for the rest.
Okay. I can do that during the exercise. But what I do wanted to, okay. Does
this part. So so to exactly your point. There is kind of a factory going on in the sense that like
you're instantiating the store that can then fetch you like the getters, the actions
that are associated with it. But at the end of the day, what is ultimately being shared,
despite it being a factory pattern, because you're using a function here, is that you have the
shared state at this top that remains a shared single-ton. Does that make sense?
Okay. So in other words, these two are not mutually exclusive. This is one example of how you can
combine them in such a way that allows you to then leverage the advantages of both. Now granted,
the read-only thing here is like, this is like call it a convention of some people just really
like having read-only values in their state stores. Honestly, typically, I haven't really had an issue
just like having the state directly accessible on my own. But teach their own and you know,
sometimes you need more guardrails for different teams. So I wanted to make sure you knew about the
use only pattern. Sorry, the read-only pattern so that it would not throw you off so much.
So basically what you'll notice is, let me show you the error ahead and why we're going to like,
do a little bit of a hybrid approach to this is you'll see here that weeks dot value is being set
to fetch weeks, right? So there's clearly some logic here that's trying to update set value.
If we look at our use week, composable right now, really the only action we have is the
fetch a week. We don't actually have an update like weeks functionality yet in terms of like,
if someone's just trying to chuck some data in. And so again, we could obviously architect that
and make that very clean. But, right, again, I want to make use of everyone's time here.
I'm just going to export this back out and then that should. And so to be very clear for the
record that defeats the purpose of the read-only in the factory. But it should solve the problem
otherwise. So this way, I don't need to do that and just have weeks exported directly. And that
actually should. Yeah. We'll start everything. Yep.